John Lawler papers, 1889-1937 (bulk 1889-1915)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
John Lawler papers, 1889-1937 (bulk 1889-1915)
AZ 179
Lawler, John, 1857-1916
10 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
John Lawler was a Prescott, Arizona businessman and cattle rancher with extensive mining interests chiefly in the Eureka Mining District, Yavapai County, Arizona, the most important of which was the Hillside Mine.
Organization
This collection is organized into eight series:
Series I: Correspondence and Personal Material, 1892-1931
Series II: Mining Business Records, 1889-1937
Series III: Banking Records
Series IV: Wiser vs. Lawler, District Court of Yavapai County, Arizona, Supreme Court of the Territory of Arizona and the U. S. Supreme Court, 1897-1902
Series V: Pick and Drill Mining Company
Series VI: Livestock and Property Records, 1890-1915
Series VII: Vouchers and Bills, 1891-1916
Series VIII: Mining Maps
Scope and Content Note
The collection includes correspondence, legal papers, assay reports, financial records, and maps relating to mining, livestock, and ranching operations, business property in Prescott, including construction of the "Lawler Block", San Diego, and Kansas City, Missouri. Some business records relate to Lawler's partnership with Edmund Wells. Also included are political correspondence with Col. John F. Wilson, U. S. Delegate from Arizona, 1902, and records of membership in various fraternal organizations.
Access Terms
Wilson, John F., 1846-1911 -- Correspondence
Wells, Edmund William, 1846-1938
Lawler and Wells (Firm) -- Records and correspondence
Seven Stars Gold Mining Company -- Records and correspondence
Pick and Drill Mining Company -- Records and correspondence
Arizona Livestock Board
Freemasons. Grand Lodge of Arizona
Hillside Mine (Ariz.)
Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Yavapai County
Gold mines and mining -- Arizona -- Yavapai County -- History -- Sources
Banks and banking -- Arizona -- Prescott -- History -- Sources
Banks and banking -- California -- San Diego -- History -- Sources
Real property -- Arizona -- Prescott -- History -- Sources
Real property -- California -- San Diego -- History -- Sources
Cattle trade -- Arizona -- History -- Sources
Prescott (Ariz.) -- Buildings -- History -- Sources
Correspondence
Ledger
Maps
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence and Personal Material, 1892-1931
  - General. 1892-1916, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Includes a letter from Mark Smith, September 14, 1910
  - Fraternal Lodge: Ancient Arabic Order of the Nobles of the Mystic Shrine, Al Malaikah Temple, Oasis of Los Angeles. 1894, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fraternal Lodge: Benevolent and Protective Order of Elks, Prescott Lodge, No. 330. 1899-1916 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fraternal Lodge: Free and Accepted Masons, Aztlan Lodge, No. 1. 1890-1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fraternal Lodge: Royal Arch Masons, Prescott Chapter, No. 2. 1890-1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fraternal Lodge: Knights Templar, Ivanhoe Commandery, No. 2. 1891-1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Political letters of Col. J. F. Wilson, delegate to Congress. 1902 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter-books. 1893-1908 (Box 1)
- Series II: Mining Business Records, 1889-1937
  - John Lawler Mines: Bills. 1889-1892 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Seven Stars Gold Mining Company: Bills. 1893 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Lawler and Wells: Vouchers. 1894-March 1906 (Box 2, Folder 3-8)
  - Lawler and Wells: Vouchers. April 1906-1910 (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
  - John Lawler Mines: Vouchers and bills. 1901-1916 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Hillside Mine: Legal papers, reports, etc. 1889-1922 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Mines: Miscellaneous papers. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Mines: Assay reports and shipping returns. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Mines: Time Book. January 1896-October 1913 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Copper Queen and Mountain Spring Mines: Legal papers, etc. 1898-1912 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Copper King and Old Dick Mines: Legal papers, etc. 1891-1908, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Various Mines: Notice of Mining Locations. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Various Mines: Legal papers, etc. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Seven Stars Mining Company: Shipments. 1892 (Volume 5)
  - Daybook. October 1892-August 1893 (Volume 6)
  - Daybook. January-June 1893 (Volume 7)
  - Ledger. May-August 1892 (Volume 8)
  - Ledger. October 1892-1893 (Volume 9)
  - Journal. September 1903-June 1915 (Volume 10)
  - Mines: Record and Order Book. 1891 (Box 11)
  - Mines: Daybook. May-October 1892 (Box 11)
  - Mines: Inventories (store, warehouse, etc.). 1895 (Box 11)
  - Mines: Seven Stars Mining Company Expense Book. 1895-1896 (Box 11)
  - Mines: Record Book (grain and hay received at Hillside Station). 1896 (Box 11)
  - Mines: Interest Ledger of John Lawler. 1891-1899 (Box 11)
  - Mines: Notes Receivable and Rent records of occupants of the Lawler Block. 1891-1902 and 1901-1932 (Box 11)
  - Mines: Daybook (Lawler and Wells). July 1903-September 1906 (Box 11)
  - Mines: Miscellaneous financial records. 1892-1893, 1906, 1908-1909 (Box 11)
- Series III: Banking Records
  - Bank of Arizona in Prescott: Miscellaneous items. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Bank of Arizona in Prescott: Checks. 1890-1916 (Box 12, Folder 2-4)
  - Yavapai County Savings Bank in Prescott. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Prescott National Bank. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Cimarron Bank in Cimarron, Kansas and other Kansas banks. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - National Bank of San Diego, San Diego, California. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous banking material. (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Wiser vs. Lawler, District Court of Yavapai County, Arizona, Supreme Court of the Territory of Arizona and the U. S. Supreme Court, 1897-1902
  - Wiser vs. Lawler: In the District Court of Yavapai County, Arizona. 1897-1898 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Includes Reporter's Transcript, Abstract of Testimony and Findings of Facts.
  - Wiser vs. Lawler: In the Supreme Court of the Territory of Arizona. 1899 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Includes a Statement, Brief and Argument for Appellees (2 copies).
  - Wiser vs. Lawler: In the Supreme Court of the United States. 1902 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Includes Statements and Brief for Respondents.
- Series V: Pick and Drill Mining Company
  - Pick and Drill Mining Company: Bills. 1911 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Pick and Drill Mining Company: Miscellaneous financial papers. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Pick and Drill Mining Company: Checks. (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Series VI: Livestock and Property Records, 1890-1915
  - Livestock: Legal papers. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Livestock: Ledger, Journal, Cattle Shipments. 1896 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Livestock: Miscellaneous Papers, including cattle brands, etc. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Arizona Livestock Sanitary Board Papers. 1901-1910 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - "Capital Block." (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - City Lots (various). (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Lawler Block: Legal papers, etc. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Lawler Block: Construction, bids, etc. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - City Taxes, Prescott. 1900-1914 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Taxes: Territorial, State, County. 1893-1913 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Lawler and Union Blocks: Vouchers. 1900-1904 (Box 15, Folder 1-6)
  - Lawler Block: Vouchers. 1905-1909, 1913-1915 (Box 16, Folder 1-5)
  - Lawler Block: Water Bills. 1900-1914 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Lawler Block: Electric Bills. 1900-1914 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - G Ranch: Legal papers. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - G Ranch: Vouchers, statements, etc. 1900-1915 (Box 17, Folder 2-5)
  - Ranch and Horses: Vouchers, etc. 1904-1907 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Brands identified in the repository finding aid.
  - Hickey Ranch: Vouchers, etc. 1904-1907 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Thompson Valley Property: Legal papers, vouchers, etc. 1884-1915 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - County Property: Miscellaneous material. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - San Diego Property: Correspondence. 1893-1908 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - San Diego Property: Legal papers. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - San Diego Property: Bills and receipts. 1890-1905 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - San Diego Property: Statements, inventory, etc. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - San Diego Property: Taxes. 1893-1909 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Property: Kansas City, Kansas and Kansas City Missouri. (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Series VII: Vouchers and Bills, 1891-1916
  - Personal: Vouchers and bills. 1891-1916 (Box 19, Folder 1-5)
  - Estate of W. and M. Lynch: Vouchers. 1900-1909 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Series VIII: Mining Maps
  - The Hillside Mines, Yavapai County, Arizona. Surveyed and drawn by Alex O. Brodie. August 1, 1892 (Box 20)
  - Map showing John Lawler's Interests in Eureka Mining District, Yavapai County, Arizona. Compiled from official surveys by H. R. Wood. (Box 20)
  - Hillside Mine Assay Section by H. R. Wood. Accompanied by a book of computations. December 1903 (Box 20)
  - Key, showing location of mining properties in the Eureka Mining District, western Yavapai County, Arizona. Possibly by H. R. Wood. September 1929 (Box 20)
  - Map of Comstock and Dexter and adjoining claims, Eureka Mining District, Yavapai County, Arizona. (Box 20)
  - Claim map of Old Dick, Eureka Mining District, Yavapai County, Arizona, by A. M. Gillespi. Data by H. R. Wood. (2 original drawings, 1 blueprint, 2 copies). (Box 20)
  - Plates of Old Dick, Copper King and Copper Queen. 1891, 1891 and 1901 (Box 20)
  - Old Dick Assay Map by H. R. Wood. December 1929 (Box 20)
  - Hillside Mine: three sectional drawings. (Box 20)
  - Township map of mine locations (original and blueprint). (Box 20)
  - Log of airport well. (Box 20)